<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Network Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/net/</guid>
      <description>This is a co-taught with the other members of the InfoLab Matteo Magnani and Christian Rohner .&#xA;Network Science is a very active and interdisciplinary research area aimed at studying physical, social and biological systems that can be modeled as sets of interconnected entities. The course covers the basics of network science, including social network analysis centrality measures (degree, betweenness, &amp;hellip;), network properties (degree distribution, average path length, &amp;hellip;), network models (Erdös-Renyi, small-world, preferential attachment), propagation (SI/SIR/SIS models, &amp;hellip;), and the main network mining tasks (position/role detection, link prediction, community detection).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral position available in Computer Science with a focus on Professional Competences and Equal Opportunities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/03/20/postdoctoral-position-available-in-computer-science-with-a-focus-on-professional-competences-and-equal-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/03/20/postdoctoral-position-available-in-computer-science-with-a-focus-on-professional-competences-and-equal-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>We are hiring a postdoctoral researcher in computer science to work at the intersection of data science, education, AI bias and equal opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD position available in Data Science for the analysis of online communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022/04/28/phd-position-available-in-data-science-for-the-analysis-of-online-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022/04/28/phd-position-available-in-data-science-for-the-analysis-of-online-communication/</guid>
      <description>I am hiring a PhD student in data science for the analysis of online communication to join the Uppsala University Information Laboratory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling online communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/conversations/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this project is to study methodologies and develop techniques and tools to monitor Social Network Sites and to identify relevant structural and communication patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and dynamics of growing networks of Reddit threads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2024working_aita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2024working_aita/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trust and media manipulation I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/proposals/trust_manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/proposals/trust_manipulation/</guid>
      <description>Social media are a key source of information for society, but it has been proven that can be also an effective source of misinformation if the readers are not critical or knowledgable enough. The goal of this project is to make a randomized controlled experiment to test if and how much sustainability experts can be manipulated.&#xA;The first part of the project consists on exploring what type of platforms we can use to run experiments like the one described below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Computational Social Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/css/</guid>
      <description>This is a new interdisciplinary course, initially developed in collaboration with Matteo Magnani (IT Department, InfoLab), Miia Bark (Department of Sociology) and Alexandra Segerberg (Department of Government) and taught for the first time in Spring 2022.&#xA;Currently the course is coordinated by Victoria Yantseva (IT Department, InfoLab).&#xA;The course introduces computational approaches to model human behavior and social phenomena. Core concepts in computational social science are covered, such as observational studies (what types of data exist, possible biases and how to use data for modeling), basic concepts and techniques for running experiments (asking vs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The limits of information consumption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2021working_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2021working_news/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controversies in sustainability narratives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023working_controversies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023working_controversies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering and Project Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/sepm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/sepm/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this course is to give both (i) basic and some advanced theoretical knowledge and (ii) practical skills in software engineering and project management. In short, in this course we will take a practical perspective, but the course also includes a fair amount of theoretical concepts and ideas. The course is structured around lectures, activities and a project.&#xA;The lectures and activities give training about all the theoretical aspects related with specifying, managing and maintaining large scale and complex software projects; emphasizing agile approaches over others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nordic Observatory for Digital Media and Information Disorder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/nordis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/nordis/</guid>
      <description>The Nordic Observatory for Digital Media and Information Disorder (NORDIS) is a consortium of researchers and fact-checkers from Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and Finland. We are one of the national hubs of The European Digital Media Observatory (EDMO).&#xA;Project Abstract The aim is to develop theories, practices and models that can help counteract digital information disorders – the spread of misinformation, disinformation and other forms of harmful information online – and to help empower citizens in the Nordic welfare states to resist such information by enabling them to enhance their media literacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soft skills in software engineering: a swedish-industry perspective from</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023working_se/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023working_se/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observing gender roles in mainstream TV shows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/proposals/gender_tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/proposals/gender_tv/</guid>
      <description>The power of mass media, such as TV shows, lies in their ability to influence our cultural and political ideas through the lens of their characters or the society they depict. In non-fictional dramas these representations can provide, for the most part and with some limitations, an accurate account of how a particular issue is perceived within a portion of the society. The goal of this project is to study how gender is represented in western TV shows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Values and Ethics in Innovation for Responsible Technology in Europe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/virt-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/virt-eu/</guid>
      <description>The goal of the project is to analyze and map the ethical practices of European hardware and software entrepreneurs, maker and hacker spaces, and community innovators in order to: (1) understand how IoT innovators enact ethics as they design future devices, (2) generate a new framework for Privacy, Ethical and Social Impact Assessment (PESIA) and (3) develop tools to support ethical reflection and self-assessment as part the design and development process for IoT technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International mobility patterns in competitive sports events</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/proposals/chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/proposals/chess/</guid>
      <description>In this project we are interested on exploring the mobility patterns of the players (e.g., how many play only national-level tournaments, what are the most visited countries/cities) across time and compare those with other competition factors (e.g., their own level, how strong is the national country of destination) in order evaluate how these inequalities can affect the ranking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Software Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/asd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/asd/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this course is to give advanced theoretical and practical knowledge for designing good software.&#xA;The main content of the course that we cover are principles and methods for software design with a special focus on object-oriented analysis and design; which includes topics such as domain modelling, software architecture, class and object modelling, behavioural modelling, design patterns, General Responsibility Assignment Software Principles (GRASP) design principles, design evaluation and improvement, and refactoring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance Programming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/courses/mp/</guid>
      <description>The main objective of the course is to teach techniques and methods for developing and extending correct, stable, maintainable and efficient software, documentation as program specification, code and memory profiling as a support for program optimising. It also touches on software developing aids and methods such as code-inspection and method-based testing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New PhD position available in Social Cybersecurity for detecting AI-based social information threads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024/05/14/new-phd-position-available-in-social-cybersecurity-for-detecting-ai-based-social-information-threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024/05/14/new-phd-position-available-in-social-cybersecurity-for-detecting-ai-based-social-information-threads/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-organizing the 1st Swedish Conference on Computational Social Science in Uppsala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024/04/23/co-organizing-the-1st-swedish-conference-on-computational-social-science-in-uppsala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024/04/23/co-organizing-the-1st-swedish-conference-on-computational-social-science-in-uppsala/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Text Network Library</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/toolkit/ttnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/toolkit/ttnet/</guid>
      <description>The ttnet (Temporal Text Network Library) is a python open source package for modelling and analizing communication networks, built on top of the uunet &amp;ndash; the core library for network modelling and analysis developed and maintained by the Uppsala University Information Laboratory . ttnet is still in an early (but continuous) development.&#xA;The library is based on the Foundations of Temporal Text Networks and Metrics for Temporal Text Networks papers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop at the The Centre for Digital Humanities Uppsala (CDHU)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024/01/18/workshop-at-the-the-centre-for-digital-humanities-uppsala-cdhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024/01/18/workshop-at-the-the-centre-for-digital-humanities-uppsala-cdhu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Sunbelt 2024 organized session &#39;Network clustering and validation: methods and applications&#39; has been approved</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/12/01/our-sunbelt-2024-organized-session-network-clustering-and-validation-methods-and-applications-has-been-approved/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/12/01/our-sunbelt-2024-organized-session-network-clustering-and-validation-methods-and-applications-has-been-approved/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigrant-critical alternative media in online conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/yantseva2023altright_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/yantseva2023altright_css/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we explore the role of immigrant-critical alternative media in shaping collective emotions and users’ evaluations of the immigration issue, using a conversational approach and an empirical case of Flashback, a prominent Swedish online platform where many immi- gration-related discussions take place. Our text and network-based analysis of more than 9,000 conversations during the last election period reveals that the platform users consume and distribute diverging types of media content across a wide ideological spectrum which, however, has a limited influence on the evolution of conversations and users’ stances in the immigration debate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User behavior influences structural properties of growing networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/goglia2023aita_poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/goglia2023aita_poster/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we study specific Reddit community, i.e., the /r/AmItheAsshole (AITA) subreddit1, from a temporal network perspective. In this subreddit people post stories about personal experience having ambiguous moral valence asking to other users if, in the narrated story, they have been ”assholes” ore not. This explicit judgement is performed by voting, i.e., writing a comment including a specific acronym corresponding to the judgement one want to express. The subreddit rules, moreover, specify that a brief motivation of the vote should be included in the comment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poster at CNA: User behavior influences structural properties of growing networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/11/29/poster-at-cna-user-behavior-influences-structural-properties-of-growing-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/11/29/poster-at-cna-user-behavior-influences-structural-properties-of-growing-networks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metrics for Temporal Text Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023temporal_chp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023temporal_chp/</guid>
      <description>Human communication, either online or offline, is characterized by when information is shared from one actor to the other and by what specific information is exchanged. Using text as a way to represent the exchanged information, we can represent human communication systems with a temporal text network model where actors and messages coexist in a dynamic multilayer network. In this model, actors and messages are represented in separate layers, connected by inter-layer temporal edges representing the communication acts—who and when communicate what information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD course in Network Science funding renewed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/10/13/phd-course-in-network-science-funding-renewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/10/13/phd-course-in-network-science-funding-renewed/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Allure of Automated Machine Learning Services: How SMEs and non-expert users can benefit from AutoML frameworks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_insurance-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_insurance-copy/</guid>
      <description>This study investigates how small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) and other resource-lacking organisations can utilise automated machine learning (AutoML) to lessen the development hurdles associated with machine learning model development. This is achieved by comparing the performance, cost of usage, as well as usability and documentation for machine learning models developed through two AutoML frameworks: Vertex AI on Google Cloud™ and the open-source library AutoGluon, developed by Amazon Web Services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dissemination of alternative media content in right-leaning online communities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023ic2s2_ttn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2023ic2s2_ttn/</guid>
      <description>In this study, we explore the dynamics of conversations on Flashback, a Swedish online forum that has more than 1.5M registered users as of February 2023 and that claims to ensure freedom of speech and users’ anonymity. Specifically, we focus on the &amp;quot;Immigration and integration&amp;quot; [Integration och invandring] subforum, where a large part of immigration-related discussions takes place. Flashback’s case is especially interesting since previous research has demonstrated that biased and Islamophobic narratives are quite common on the platform (Kaati et al.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk at IC2S2 2023: The dissemination of alternative media content in right-leaning online communities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/07/17/talk-at-ic2s2-2023-the-dissemination-of-alternative-media-content-in-right-leaning-online-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/07/17/talk-at-ic2s2-2023-the-dissemination-of-alternative-media-content-in-right-leaning-online-communities/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Extraction of Insurance Policy Information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_insurance/</guid>
      <description>This thesis investigates Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques to extract relevant information from long and unstructured insurance policy documents. The goal is to reduce the amount of time required by readers to understand the coverage within the documents. The study uses predefined insurance policy coverage parameters, created by industry experts to represent what is covered in the policy documents. Three NLP approaches are used to classify the text sequences as insurance parameter classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Ownership of Personal data in the Cloud by Optimizing the IT Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_architecture/</guid>
      <description>Cloud computing is an area that many companies use in order to stay in line with technological development. To keep these systems productive and easily managed, a reference architecture can be used as a framework and also as a manual on how to structure an organization to suit its specific needs and goals. The reference architecture can make it easier to divide responsibility as well as working tasks within an organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote talk at ARS&#39;23 Ninth International Workshop on Social Network Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/05/03/keynote-talk-at-ars23-ninth-international-workshop-on-social-network-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023/05/03/keynote-talk-at-ars23-ninth-international-workshop-on-social-network-analysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International mobility patterns in competitive sports events</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_chess/</guid>
      <description>Competitive chess is a sports category where players can freely participate in most of the competitions around the world without restriction - as opposed of other individual sports, where you must qualify in order to participate. In this project we were interested on exploring the mobility patterns of the players (e.g., how many play only national-level tournaments, what are the most visited countries/cities) across time and compare those with other competition factors (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Network Analysis Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2023_platform/</guid>
      <description>The design of scalable solutions to analyze large complex data from social media have been an ongoing research problem with practical applications. The purpose of the project was to deploy a scalable computing architecture able to process real-time social media data, allowing data scientist to analyze temporal and linguistics trends in real-time.&#xA;In particular, during this project the students aimed at (a) understanding how and what type of data we want to process and (b) implementing and evaluate a scalable solution to process and visualize large-scale data streams as complex networks in real time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robustness and Sensitivity of Network-Based Topic Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/galluccio022cna_txt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/galluccio022cna_txt/</guid>
      <description>In the context of textual analysis, network-based procedures for topic detection are gaining attention as an alternative to classical topic models. Network-based procedures are based on the idea that documents can be represented as word co-occurrence networks, where topics are defined as groups of strongly connected words. Although many works have used network-based procedures for topic detection, there is a lack of systematic analysis of how different design choices, such as the building of the word co-occurrence matrix and the selection of the community detection algorithm, affect the final results in terms of detected topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Conversation around NATO in the Nordic States Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_nato/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_nato/</guid>
      <description>Online communication is makes up a large part of the public discourse around current events, and increasingly has been the target for disinformation campaigns. Clearly, there is a need for some language-agnostic tool to map how the discourse shifts and evolves. As such, the goal of this analysis was to create a tool to collate posts from Facebook, Instagram, Reddit and Twitter into one dataset for comparison and analysis, then to generate weekly topics based off posts containing the term “NATO” from this dataset.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Portrayal of the 2022 Russian Invasion of Ukraine on Social Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_invasion/</guid>
      <description>Everyday communication consists of a complex of information, objective, and subjective. The meaning one tries to convey may hide certain attitudes, opinions, or even an attempt to influence the other, whether it is done knowingly or not. This can be achieved by analysing the content, such as its structure, grammar, and vocabulary. Social media as a form of communication is no exception to this fact. Discourse can be analysed by taking into account the underlying discursive production and interpret it in relation to this contextual understanding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring How Swedish News are Framed Online</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_newspapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_newspapers/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of the project was to conduct a comparative study of how Swedish media - mainly online newspapers - might influence the public agenda by, knowingly or unknowingly, framing their news articles in a particular way. The project, therefore, aims at analyzing the language characteristics (e.g., topics, sentiments, polarization of ideas) of the news articles already collected from some of the most visited online newspapers and compare if there is a clear difference on how they choose to portrait some news, rather than others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Scalable Platform for Data-Intensive Visualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2022_platform/</guid>
      <description>A huge variety of social applications, such as Twitter and Instagram, have been developed over the last few decades. With the introduction of these online social networks, there has never been a better time to research human interaction on a worldwide scale. The goal of this project is to use a scalable and high-performance Twitter data visualization platform to investigate Twitter data on a given topic in real-time.&#xA;To create a scalable Twitter data visualization platform, we write a basic version of the system using the Twitter Developer Platform&amp;rsquo;s real-time and non-real-time APIs, optimize the frontend and backend performance with various components, and devise a benchmarking testing scheme to see if the application meets the scalability and high-performance requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophie Germain program grant, Computational methods and news framing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2022/04/05/sophie-germain-program-grant-computational-methods-and-news-framing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2022/04/05/sophie-germain-program-grant-computational-methods-and-news-framing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chydenius Medal awarded to the NORDIS project for defending democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/12/02/chydenius-medal-awarded-to-the-nordis-project-for-defending-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/12/02/chydenius-medal-awarded-to-the-nordis-project-for-defending-democracy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New postdoc position available in Computational Social Science / Social Data Science for the analysis of online disinformation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/09/28/new-postdoc-position-available-in-computational-social-science-/-social-data-science-for-the-analysis-of-online-disinformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/09/28/new-postdoc-position-available-in-computational-social-science-/-social-data-science-for-the-analysis-of-online-disinformation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We lunch the NORDIS project: Nordic Observatory for Digital Media and Information Disorder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/09/15/we-lunch-the-nordis-project-nordic-observatory-for-digital-media-and-information-disorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/09/15/we-lunch-the-nordis-project-nordic-observatory-for-digital-media-and-information-disorder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hugo-Uppsala Theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/toolkit/hugo_uppsala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/toolkit/hugo_uppsala/</guid>
      <description>The hugo-Uppsala is an academic theme I developed over the years to build my personal webpage. This theme has been inspited by the Hugo Finisterre theme by Jonathan Gilligan and some other academics&amp;rsquo; personal pages I have visited in the past.&#xA;The theme supports most of the features from Hugo Finisterre, such as the automatic generation of publication lists from BibTeX files and the dynamic generation of news in the homepage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uppsala University Network Library</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/toolkit/multinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/toolkit/multinet/</guid>
      <description>The uunet (Uppsala University Network Library) is the C++ open source core library for network modelling and analysis developed and maintained by the Uppsala University Information Laboratory . The library is fully documented and includes a comperhensive test suite with examples that demonstrate how it can be used or extended.&#xA;This library also provides most of the code behind the R and Python multinet libraries, which are more specialized.&#xA;The multinet R library The multinet library is available on CRAN (the Comprehensive R Archive Network), and can be installed directly from an R terminal or RStudio.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On a quest to identify online conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2021networks_ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2021networks_ttt/</guid>
      <description>Human-generated information underlies nearly every aspect of our lives. With the rise of affordable handheld and embedded IoT devices with new connectivity capabilities and the ever-increasing integration of many technologies with social media platforms, most social problem-solving processes are increasingly relying on online conversations and textual communication. However, unlike in a face-to-face situation, where we can fairly recognise which conversations are co-occurring around us and their participants, automatically identifying cohesive conversations online is a challenging task.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Multiplex Social Networks with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/magnani2021mpx_lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/magnani2021mpx_lib/</guid>
      <description>Multiplex social networks are characterized by a common set of actors connected through multiple types of relations. The multinet package provides a set of R functions to analyze multiplex social networks within the more general framework of multilayer networks, where each type of relation is represented as a layer in the network. The package contains functions to import/export, create and manipulate multilayer networks, implementations of several state-of-the-art multiplex network analysis algorithms, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JSS paper with Matteo Magnani and Luca Rossi: Analysis of Multiplex Social Networks with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/06/02/jss-paper-with-matteo-magnani-and-luca-rossi-analysis-of-multiplex-social-networks-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/06/02/jss-paper-with-matteo-magnani-and-luca-rossi-analysis-of-multiplex-social-networks-with-r/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk at Networks 2021: On a quest to identify online conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/05/21/talk-at-networks-2021-on-a-quest-to-identify-online-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2021/05/21/talk-at-networks-2021-on-a-quest-to-identify-online-conversations/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Twitter-Based Study of the European Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/funda2020iot_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/funda2020iot_sna/</guid>
      <description>We present a methodology integrating social media data, data from qualitative research and network analysis. Qualitative insights gained from ethnographic fieldwork are used to collect and annotate social network data, and social media data is used as part of the ethnography to identify relevant actors and topics. The methodology is presented in the context of an analysis of the Internet of Things in the European context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listening in on Productivity: Applying the Four Key Metrics to measure productivity in a software development company</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2021_productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2021_productivity/</guid>
      <description>Software development is an area in which companies not only need to keep up with the latest technology, but they additionally need to continuously increase their productivity to stay competitive in the industry. One company currently facing these challenges is Storytel - one of the strongest players on the Swedish audiobook market - with about a fourth of all employees involved with software development, and a rapidly growing workforce.&#xA;With the purpose of understanding how the Storytel Tech Department is performing, this thesis maps Storytel’s productivity defined through the Four Key Metrics - Deployment Frequency, Delivery Lead Time, Mean Time To Restore and Change Fail Rate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of Swedish Newspapers Using Topic Detection and Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2021_newspapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2021_newspapers/</guid>
      <description>Newspapers might report on the same event, say a sport event or a political statement, but since they most likely differ in the presentation, are the content and under laying message of the articles actually the same? A human can read two separate articles and determine if they touch similar subjects and if they approach the subject in a positive or negative way. If this comparison would be preformed over several thousand of articles a computer would very much be the preferred method.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic blockmodeling methods for bipartite graphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2021_sbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2021_sbm/</guid>
      <description>Stochastic block models (SBM) are generative models for network structures such as communities, sets of nodes characterized by being more densely connected with one another than with the rest of the network. One of the main advantages of generative models, such as SBM, is that they open the door to inference: if we are given a network G, we can use techniques from statistical inference to estimate the values of θ that best explain or reproduce the observed pattern of connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of the Consequences of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) on Social Network Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/kostios2019gdpr_nhb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/kostios2019gdpr_nhb/</guid>
      <description>We present a methodology integrating social media data, data from qualitative research and network analysis. Qualitative insights gained from ethnographic fieldwork are used to collect and annotate social network data, and social media data is used as part of the ethnography to identify relevant actors and topics. The methodology is presented in the context of an analysis of the Internet of Things in the European context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uppsala University grant for course &#34;Introduction to Computational Social Science&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2020/06/22/uppsala-university-grant-for-course-introduction-to-computational-social-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2020/06/22/uppsala-university-grant-for-course-introduction-to-computational-social-science/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilayer network simplification: Approaches, models and methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/interdonato2020mpx_spl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/interdonato2020mpx_spl/</guid>
      <description>Multilayer networks have been widely used to represent and analyze systems of interconnected entities where both the entities and their connections can be of different types. However, real multilayer networks can be difficult to analyze because of irrelevant information, such as layers not related to the objective of the analysis, because of their size, or because traditional methods defined to analyze simple networks do not have a straightforward extension able to handle multiple layers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A system for GDPR-compliant collection of social media data: from legal to software requirements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2019_gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2019_gdpr/</guid>
      <description>As of 2018 there is a new regulation regarding data protection in the European union. The legislation, often refereed to as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), has led to increased demands on organizations that processes personal data. This thesis has investigated the legal consequences of social media data collection with a certain focus on collection of tweets. The legal findings was then translated into possible enhancements of a tweet collecting software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text to features for Swedish text</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2019_text_features_swedish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2019_text_features_swedish/</guid>
      <description>In text mining, texts are usually transformed into numerical vectors or feature vectors, before they are given to a machine learning algorithm for text classification. In this project, a set of features for classifying tweets in Swedish was created. The following classification tasks were selected: gender, age and political party prediction, sentiment analysis and authorship attribution, which is the task of determining if a text was written by a particular author or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metrics for Temporal Text Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019temporal_chp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019temporal_chp/</guid>
      <description>Human communication, either online or offline, is characterized by when information is shared from one actor to the other and by what specific information is exchanged. Using text as a way to represent the exchanged information, we can represent human communication systems with a temporal text network model where actors and messages coexist in a dynamic multilayer network. In this model, actors and messages are represented in separate layers, connected by inter-layer temporal edges representing the communication acts—who and when communicate what information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observing the tech, using MeetUp data to study the evolution of the discourse around IoT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/luca2019aoir_meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/luca2019aoir_meetup/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes to use MeetUp data to study the emergence and the evolution of the technological trend commonly known as Internet of Things (IoT). Starting from a manually selected sample of 220 European MeetUp groups we used MeetUp&#39;s APIs, to retrieve additional information about the events and participating users. The final dataset consists of 220 groups, 32967 members and 2386 events from 2011 until now (Jan 2019). The results suggest the presence of clearly identifiable European hubs for IoT development but a worldwide crowd of users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Detection in Bipartite Temporal Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_pattern_bbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_pattern_bbt/</guid>
      <description>Pattern detection in social networks has been of great interest recently because it helps to reveal insights about how people communicate. In graph mining, this is referred to as a frequent sub-graphs mining problem and it has many variations regarding the structure of the network - i.e. how much information the graph holds. As a part of the evolution of the problem, additional information such as data dimensions or more advanced network structure are incorporated to the input to find more interesting hidden patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal text networks: foundations and applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019ic2s2_ttn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019ic2s2_ttn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Challenge Competition 2019</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_cyberchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_cyberchallenge/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of a simulated national thread scenario and creation/defense of a policy brief document</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measure development and social media analysis using temporal text networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_analysis_ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_analysis_ttt/</guid>
      <description>The widespread social media usage generates an immense amount of data. Data which is highly beneficial to several domains whether monetary or research based. Various models exist to extract this data however analysis tend to be restrictive. The temporal text network model is a dynamic network model built upon the foundation of temporal networks. It provides text as a variable and considers messages passed between users while maintaining the time of transmission, making it suitable for social media analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From interaction to participation: the role of the imagined audience in social media community detection and an application to political communication on Twitter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/obaida2018asonam_ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/obaida2018asonam_ttt/</guid>
      <description>In the context of community detection in online social media, a lot of effort has been put into the definition of sophisticated network clustering algorithms and much less on the equally crucial process of obtaining high-quality input data. User-interaction data explicitly provided by social media platforms has largely been used as the main source of data because of its easy accessibility. However, this data does not capture a fundamental and much more frequent type of participatory behavior where users do not explicitly mention others but direct their messages to an invisible audience following a common hashtag.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of Temporal Text Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2018ans_ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2018ans_ttt/</guid>
      <description>Three fundamental elements to understand human information networks are the individuals (actors) in the network, the information they exchange, that is often observable online as text content (emails, social media posts, etc.), and the time when these exchanges happen. An extremely large amount of research has addressed some of these aspects either in isolation or as combinations of two of them. There are also more and more works studying systems where all three elements are present, but typically using ad hoc models and algorithms that cannot be easily transferred to other contexts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of Temporal Text Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2018sunbelt_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2018sunbelt_sna/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few years online social media have been frequently used as a way to explain human social behavior around a particular area of interest. Examples include voting, political sentiment, psychological well-being and disaster response. The public accessibility of several sources allows us to observe these phenomena at various scales, from conversations among small groups of individuals to the effects on large communities. To cope with the complexity of online information, researchers have typically focused on either the topology of the interactions, as commonly done in Network Science, or the text exchanged among individuals, using methods from Computational Linguistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text networks: foundations and structural analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2017complex_txt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2017complex_txt/</guid>
      <description>A large amount of human generated information is available online in the form of text exchanged between individuals or groups. Examples include social network sites, on- line forums and emails. The public accessibility of several of these sources allows us to observe our society at various scales, from conversations among small groups of individuals to the effects of misinformation on large communities. To cope with the complexity of online information, researchers have typically focused on either the topology of the network, as commonly done in Network Science, or the text exchanged among individuals, using methods from Computational Linguistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilayer analysis of online illicit marketplaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/ashcroft2016silkroad_poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/ashcroft2016silkroad_poster/</guid>
      <description>The content of Online Illicit Marketplaces (OIMs) on the Dark Web has been studied using different approaches. For example, qualitative ethnographic studies to understand the markets&#39; social dynamics have produced interesting descriptions of specific sites, contexts and behaviours [1]; but given the large amount of data exchanged on several markets a manual qualitative analysis can only provide a partial view of these systems. Therefore, more quantitative approaches have been used (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Network-Aware Service Placement in Community Network Micro-Clouds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/selimi2016europar_top/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/selimi2016europar_top/</guid>
      <description>Cloud services in community networks have been enabled by micro-cloud providers. They form community network micro-clouds (CNMCs), which grow organically, i.e. without being planned and optimized beforehand. Services running in community networks face specific challenges intrinsic to these infrastructures, such as the limited capacity of nodes and links, their dynamics and geographic distribution. CNMCs are used to deploy distributed applications, such as streaming and storage services, which transfer significant amounts of data between the nodes on which they run.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new approach to role and position detection in networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2016snam_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2016snam_sna/</guid>
      <description>We rethink and extend the concepts of position and role in a network, basing them on various well-known measures that were not previously associated with these concepts, such as geodesic distance and modularity. The effectiveness of our new role and position detection algorithms is evaluated both qualitatively and quantitatively, on synthetic and real data, showing that we can identify new types of meaningful patterns in networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Indirect Blockmodeling for Monitoring Students Roles in Collaborative Learning Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2016cscwd_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2016cscwd_sna/</guid>
      <description>Collaborative learning activities have shown to be useful to address educational processes in several contexts. Monitoring these activities is mandatory to determine the quality of the collaboration and learning processes. Recent research works propose using Social Network Analysis techniques to understand students’ collaboration learning process during these experiences. Aligned with that, this paper proposes the use of the indirect blockmodeling network analytic technique for monitoring the behaviour of different social roles played by students in collaborative learning scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incentives for sharing heterogeneous resources in distributed systems: a participatory approach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015phd_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015phd_thesis/</guid>
      <description>Contributory and volunteer computing ecosystems built around a community of participants need, like any other common-pool resources, an adaptive governance mechanism to guarantee the sustainability of the ecosystem. Reciprocity incentive mechanisms based on economic principles have been proved efficient solutions to regulate the resource sharing and allocation in large computing architectures, guaranteeing a direct retribution for each individual contribution even in presence of misbehaving users. However, while these mechanisms preserve the macro-equilibrium of the computational shared resources (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis to Predict Link Quality of Wireless Community Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/millan2015comnet_lq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/millan2015comnet_lq/</guid>
      <description>Community networks have emerged under the mottos “break the strings that are limiting you”, “don&#39;t buy the network, be the network” or “a free net for everyone is possible”. Such networks create a measurable social impact as they provide to the community the right and opportunity of communication. As any other network that mixes wired and wireless links, the routing protocol must face several challenges that arise from the unreliable nature of the wireless medium.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Technological Overview of the Guifi.net Community Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015comnet_top/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015comnet_top/</guid>
      <description>This work presents a technological analysis of guifi.net, a free, neutral, and open-access community network. Guifi.net consists of more than 27,000 operational nodes, which makes it the world’s largest community network in terms of the number of nodes and coverage area. This paper describes the characteristics of the network, the link level topology, its growth over a decade, and its resilience in terms of availability and reachability of network nodes. Our study is based on open data published by guifi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role and position detection in networks: reloaded</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015asonam_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015asonam_sna/</guid>
      <description>Roles and positions are structural components in complex social systems which group actors based on how similarly they are connected to the rest of the actors. Role and position detection methods have been successfully used to evaluate and understand the dynamics of social networks and the behavior of their members. However, actor similarities used to detect positions have been based on pairwise comparisons so far: e.g., structural equivalence states that Alice and Bob are in the same position if they are both connected or not to the same other actors in the network, one by one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detection of roles and positions in multi-layer social networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015sunbelt_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015sunbelt_sna/</guid>
      <description>The detection of social positions and roles is one of the key tasks in the structural analysis of complex social systems. Traditionally, structural analysis methods are able to identify local and global roles and positions in networks with one or more types of relations. However, the classical way to deal with a multi-layer network consists on either (a) individually identifying positions in each layer at a time, then studying their relationships or (b) flattening the social network into a mono-relational graph and apply some of the existing blockmodeling techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motivating the non-technical participation in technical communities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015jcsd_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015jcsd_sna/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motivating the non-technical participation in technical communities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015cscwd_rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2015cscwd_rs/</guid>
      <description>Technical communities are social structures that emerge around the interest of individuals to build and deploy their own technology or communication infrastructure, such as wireless community networks. In these communities, the access to shared resources is regulated by incentive mechanisms, which are usually based on the members’ contributions. Typically, technical contributions are computed by these mechanisms, ignoring the non-technical activities that members voluntarily perform to keep the community alive, e.g., administration and coordination of the tasks performed by the sub-communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Social Effort in Multiplex Participatory Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014gecon_sna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014gecon_sna/</guid>
      <description>Community networks are participatory connectivity solutions for citizens where all the resources are owned, managed and controlled by the participants. As a natural evolution, in recent years some initiatives have flourished to provide higher level services based on volunteer computing and resource sharing paradigms. A fundamental aspect of these paradigms is user participation. In this work, we apply some social mining techniques aiming to identify the roles of the individuals in the social network behind a community network, here Guifi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Collaboration in Volunteer Computing Systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014jucs_rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014jucs_rs/</guid>
      <description>Volunteer computing is a paradigm in which devices participating in a distributed environment share part of their resources to help others perform their activities. The effectiveness of this computing paradigm depends on the collaboration attitude adopted by the participating devices. Unfortunately for software designers it is not clear how to contribute with local resources to the shared environment without compromising resources that could then be required by the contributors. Therefore, many designers adopt a conservative position when defining the collaboration strategy to be embedded in volunteer computing applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring local service allocation in Community Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014wimob_all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014wimob_all/</guid>
      <description>Community Cloud computing is a new trend on cloud computing that aims to build service infrastructures upon Wireless Community Networks taking advantage of underused community physical resources. Service allocation protocols are a key design challenge that all cloud systems must properly address to optimize resource utilization. They are specially important when cloud services require a Quality of Service (QoS) and network stability or performance (delay, jitter, minimum bandwidth) cannot be guaranteed a-priory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking and predicting link quality in wireless community networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/millan2014cnbub_lq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/millan2014cnbub_lq/</guid>
      <description>Community networks have emerged under the mottos of “break the strings that are limiting you”, don&amp;amp;#x27;t buy the network, be the network&amp;amp;#x27;&amp;amp;#x27; or a free net for everyone is possible&#39;&#39;. Such networks create a measurable social impact as they provide to the community the right and opportunity of communication. As any other network that mixes wired and wireless links, the routing protocol must face several challenges that arise from the unreliable nature of the wireless medium.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud-Based Extension for Community-Lab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/menan2014mascots_demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/menan2014mascots_demo/</guid>
      <description>Community-Lab is an open, distributed infrastructure for researchers to carry out experiments within wireless community networks. Community networks are an emergent model of infrastructures built with off-the-shelf communication equipment that aims to satisfy a community&#39;s demand for Internet access and ICT services. Community-Lab consists of more than 100 nodes that are integrated in existing community networks, thus giving researchers access to community networks and allowing them to conduct experimental evaluation of routing protocols, services and applications deployed there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the web proxy service of a community network: Guifi.net</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014jcsd_lq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2014jcsd_lq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community home gateways for {P2P} clouds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/escrich2013p2p_poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/escrich2013p2p_poster/</guid>
      <description>We present the community home gateway, a computer system attached to a wireless community network router, able to host platform and application services. Different to current home gateways and other low-end systems, the community home gateway offers resource virtualization, and can thus be used as a cloud resource. Furthermore, it removes the lack of a home gateway system that is open for service contributions and therefore constitutes an important step towards building P2P clouds with low-end devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effort-based incentives for resource sharing in collaborative volunteer applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2013cscwd_rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2013cscwd_rs/</guid>
      <description>Collaborative and volunteer applications need to implement incentive mechanisms to regulate resource sharing and encourage network nodes to contribute for reaching a certain goal. Typically, these incentive mechanisms assign resources to network node requests, based on the total amount of resources contributed by the requesting participant. This approach assumes that participants contributing more should also get back more resources from the collaborative environment. This assumption turns the system unfair to those participants with scarce resources, because they have just few resources to share.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incentivos basados en el esfuerzo para compartir recursos en aplicaciones colaborativas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2013jcsd_rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2013jcsd_rs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying applications with Community-Lab in wireless community networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/aymerich2013wowmon_demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/aymerich2013wowmon_demo/</guid>
      <description>Community-Lab is a testbed for researchers to carry out experiments within wireless community networks. Community networks are an emergent model of infrastructures built with off-the-shelf communication equipment that aims to satisfy a community&#39;s demand for Internet access and ICT services. Community-Lab consists of a set of nodes that are integrated in existing community networks, thus giving researchers access to community networks and allowing them to conduct experimental evaluation of applications deployed there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing hardware resources in heterogeneous computer-supported collaboration scenarios</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2013icae_top/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2013icae_top/</guid>
      <description>There currently are many mobile computing devices with various properties and capabilities. These devices may need to collaborate among them to allow nomad workers to perform a common activity. Unfortunately software developers in charge of creating infrastructures or applications allowing these devices to cooperate among them, do not count with clear guidelines to design such software components; particularly when these components must work in a scenario involving heterogeneous devices. This paper presents a study that tries to understand how to address collaboration among heterogeneous mobile devices, by exploring several variables affecting the process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topology patterns of a community network: Guifi.net</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2012cnbub_top/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2012cnbub_top/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a measurement study of the topology and its effect on usage of Guifi.net, a large-scale community network. It focuses on the main issues faced by community network and lessons to consider for its future growth in order to preserve its scalability, stability and openness. The results show the network topology as an atypical high density Scale-Free network with critical points of failure and poor gateway selection or placement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Node Placement Heuristic to Encourage Resource Sharing in Mobile Computing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2011iccsa_top/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2011iccsa_top/</guid>
      <description>Advances in wireless communication systems and mobile devices allow nomad users to participate in mobile collaborative activities. However the availability of hardware resources of the mobile devices that are participating in the collaboration process is a crucial factor that can enhance or jeopardize such activity. This paper studies how the network topology and the hardware resources distributed into a network influence the collaboration among the participants in the activities. The results obtained from simulating the strategy of resource sharing in an overlay network allowed us to observe two clear implications: (1) it is important to maximize the number of links between Desktop PC and mobile devices and (2) the mobile devices have to be placed within the network topology in the nodes with higher degree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing the effects of sharing hardware resources in mobile collaboration scenarios</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2011cscwd_top/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2011cscwd_top/</guid>
      <description>Advances in wireless communication systems and mobile devices allow nomad users to participate in mobile collaborative activities. However the availability of hardware resources in the mobile devices participating in the collaboration process enhances or jeopardizes such activity. This paper studies how the network topology and the hardware resources distributed into a mobile network influence the collaboration activities among the participants. Several simulations were done to try to understand this issue. The obtained results show that in mobile collaboration scenarios involving a high number of resources-constraint mobile devices (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diseño e implementación de un simulador para explorar la cooperación en entornos distribuidos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2011jcsd_simluator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2011jcsd_simluator/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and implementation of a simulator to explore cooperation in distributed environments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2010msc_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2010msc_thesis/</guid>
      <description>The lack of computational resources on personal computers, in addition to evident increasingly of requirements in the current software, needs a imperative redefinition of computing paradigms that existed until now. The distributed computing networks are the currently solutions that are being evaluated to solve the problem with the lack of hardware resources. However, the implementation of these solutions is stopped by the lack of knowledge about its functioning and the need to resolve technological problems that research and innovation have not yet discovered how.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programació i avaluació de la capa de transport per al sistema de visualització distribuïda SAGE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2008bsc_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2008bsc_thesis/</guid>
      <description>La fundació i2CAT, dins del projecte de recerca V3 (Video, Videoconferència i Visualització en HD), treballa actualment en una solució de videoconferència en Alta Definició que utilitza el software SAGE (Scalable Adaptive Graphics Environment) per visualitzar la informació que es rep en una graella de pantalles de 1200 per 1600 píxels. El rendiment actual d’aquesta part de recepció és força baix, de forma que es fa impossible la visualització de fluxos més grans de 600 Mbps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/funda2019working_iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/funda2019working_iot/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/funda2020working_meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/funda2020working_meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019working_bipartite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019working_bipartite/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019working_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pubs/vega2019working_education/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
