<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</title>
    <link>https://davidevega.eu/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidevega.eu/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modeling online communication</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/research/conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/research/conversations/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this project is to study methodologies and develop techniques and tools to monitor Social Network Sites and to identify relevant structural and communication patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nordic Observatory for Digital Media and Information Disorder</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/research/nordis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/research/nordis/</guid>
      <description>The Nordic Observatory for Digital Media and Information Disorder (NORDIS) is a consortium of researchers and fact-checkers from Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and Finland. We are one of the national hubs of The European Digital Media Observatory (EDMO).&#xA;Project Abstract The aim is to develop theories, practices and models that can help counteract digital information disorders – the spread of misinformation, disinformation and other forms of harmful information online – and to help empower citizens in the Nordic welfare states to resist such information by enabling them to enhance their media literacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Values and Ethics in Innovation for Responsible Technology in Europe</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/research/virt-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/research/virt-eu/</guid>
      <description>The goal of the project is to analyze and map the ethical practices of European hardware and software entrepreneurs, maker and hacker spaces, and community innovators in order to: (1) understand how IoT innovators enact ethics as they design future devices, (2) generate a new framework for Privacy, Ethical and Social Impact Assessment (PESIA) and (3) develop tools to support ethical reflection and self-assessment as part the design and development process for IoT technologies.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
