<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Engineering on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</title>
    <link>https://davidevega.eu/tags/software-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Engineering on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidevega.eu/tags/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Ownership of Personal data in the Cloud by Optimizing the IT Architecture</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2023_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2023_architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing is an area that many companies use in order to stay in line with technological development. To keep these systems productive and easily managed, a reference architecture can be used as a framework and also as a manual on how to structure an organization to suit its specific needs and goals. The reference architecture can make it easier to divide responsibility as well as working tasks within an organization. One company facing the challenges that comes with cloud based systems is Vattenfall, one of the biggest energy companies in Europe. An organization like Vattenfall handles a great load of customer data which is to be controlled and protected in every way. In order to keep on making sure that these systems are efficient and secure, a reference architecture could be a helpful tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listening in on Productivity: Applying the Four Key Metrics to measure productivity in a software development company</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software development is an area in which companies not only need to keep up with the latest technology, but they additionally need to continuously increase their productivity to stay competitive in the industry. One company currently facing these challenges is Storytel - one of the strongest players on the Swedish audiobook market - with about a fourth of all employees involved with software development, and a rapidly growing workforce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the purpose of understanding how the Storytel Tech Department is performing, this thesis maps Storytel’s productivity defined through the Four Key Metrics - Deployment Frequency, Delivery Lead Time, Mean Time To Restore and Change Fail Rate. A classification is made into which performance category (Low, Medium, High, Elite) the Storytel Tech Department belongs to through a deep-dive into the raw system data existing at Storytel, mainly focusing on the case management system Jira. A survey of the Tech Department was conducted, to give insights into the connection between human and technical factors influencing productivity (categorized into Culture, Environment, and Process) and estimated productivity. Along with these data collections, interviews with Storytel employees were performed to gather further knowledge about the Tech Department, and to understand potential bottlenecks and obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
