<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</title>
    <link>https://davidevega.eu/toolkit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidevega.eu/toolkit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>hugo-Uppsala Theme</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/toolkit/hugo_uppsala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/toolkit/hugo_uppsala/</guid>
      <description>The hugo-Uppsala is an academic theme I developed over the years to build my personal webpage. This theme has been inspited by the Hugo Finisterre theme by Jonathan Gilligan and some other academics&amp;rsquo; personal pages I have visited in the past.
The theme supports most of the features from Hugo Finisterre, such as the automatic generation of publication lists from BibTeX files and the dynamic generation of news in the homepage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uppsala University Network Library</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/toolkit/multinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/toolkit/multinet/</guid>
      <description>The uunet (Uppsala University Network Library) is the C++ open source core library for network modelling and analysis developed and maintained by the Uppsala University Information Laboratory . The library is fully documented and includes a comperhensive test suite with examples that demonstrate how it can be used or extended.
This library also provides most of the code behind the R and Python multinet libraries, which are more specialized.
The multinet R library The multinet library is available on CRAN (the Comprehensive R Archive Network), and can be installed directly from an R terminal or RStudio.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
