<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ttt on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ttt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ttt on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ttt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Detection in Bipartite Temporal Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_pattern_bbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_pattern_bbt/</guid>
      <description>Pattern detection in social networks has been of great interest recently because it helps to reveal insights about how people communicate. In graph mining, this is referred to as a frequent sub-graphs mining problem and it has many variations regarding the structure of the network - i.e. how much information the graph holds. As a part of the evolution of the problem, additional information such as data dimensions or more advanced network structure are incorporated to the input to find more interesting hidden patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measure development and social media analysis using temporal text networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_analysis_ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/projects/2018_analysis_ttt/</guid>
      <description>The widespread social media usage generates an immense amount of data. Data which is highly beneficial to several domains whether monetary or research based. Various models exist to extract this data however analysis tend to be restrictive. The temporal text network model is a dynamic network model built upon the foundation of temporal networks. It provides text as a variable and considers messages passed between users while maintaining the time of transmission, making it suitable for social media analysis.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
