<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</title>
    <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Davide Vega D&#39;Aurelio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidevega.eu/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trust and media manipulation I</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/proposals/trust_manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/proposals/trust_manipulation/</guid>
      <description>Social media are a key source of information for society, but it has been proven that can be also an effective source of misinformation if the readers are not critical or knowledgable enough. The goal of this project is to make a randomized controlled experiment to test if and how much sustainability experts can be manipulated.
The first part of the project consists on exploring what type of platforms we can use to run experiments like the one described below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering and Project Management</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/sepm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/sepm/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this course is to give both (i) basic and some advanced theoretical knowledge and (ii) practical skills in software engineering and project management. In short, in this course we will take a practical perspective, but the course also includes a fair amount of theoretical concepts and ideas. The course is structured around lectures, activities and a project.
The lectures and activities give training about all the theoretical aspects related with specifying, managing and maintaining large scale and complex software projects; emphasizing agile approaches over others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing gender roles in mainstream TV shows</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/proposals/gender_tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/proposals/gender_tv/</guid>
      <description>The power of mass media, such as TV shows, lies in their ability to influence our cultural and political ideas through the lens of their characters or the society they depict. In non-fictional dramas these representations can provide, for the most part and with some limitations, an accurate account of how a particular issue is perceived within a portion of the society. The goal of this project is to study how gender is represented in western TV shows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Software Design</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/asd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/asd/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this course is to give advanced theoretical and practical knowledge for designing good software.
The main content of the course that we cover are principles and methods for software design with a special focus on object-oriented analysis and design; which includes topics such as domain modelling, software architecture, class and object modelling, behavioural modelling, design patterns, General Responsibility Assignment Software Principles (GRASP) design principles, design evaluation and improvement, and refactoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International mobility patterns in competitive sports events</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/proposals/chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/proposals/chess/</guid>
      <description>In this project we are interested on exploring the mobility patterns of the players (e.g., how many play only national-level tournaments, what are the most visited countries/cities) across time and compare those with other competition factors (e.g., their own level, how strong is the national country of destination) in order evaluate how these inequalities can affect the ranking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance Programming</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/mp/</guid>
      <description>The main objective of the course is to teach techniques and methods for developing and extending correct, stable, maintainable and efficient software, documentation as program specification, code and memory profiling as a support for program optimising. It also touches on software developing aids and methods such as code-inspection and method-based testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Computational Social Science</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/courses/css/</guid>
      <description>This is a new interdisciplinary course I am currently developing in collaboration with Matteo Magnani (IT Department, InfoLab), Miia Bark (Department of Sociology) and Alexandra Segerberg (Department of Government) and it will be taught for the first time in Spring 2022.
The course introduces computational approaches to model human behaviour and social phenomena. Core concepts in computational social science are covered, such as observational studies (what types of data exist, possible biases and how to use data for modelling), basic concepts and techniques for running experiments (asking vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening in on Productivity: Applying the Four Key Metrics to measure productivity in a software development company</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_productivity/</guid>
      <description>Software development is an area in which companies not only need to keep up with the latest technology, but they additionally need to continuously increase their productivity to stay competitive in the industry. One company currently facing these challenges is Storytel - one of the strongest players on the Swedish audiobook market - with about a fourth of all employees involved with software development, and a rapidly growing workforce.
With the purpose of understanding how the Storytel Tech Department is performing, this thesis maps Storytel’s productivity defined through the Four Key Metrics - Deployment Frequency, Delivery Lead Time, Mean Time To Restore and Change Fail Rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of Swedish Newspapers Using Topic Detection and Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_newspapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_newspapers/</guid>
      <description>Newspapers might report on the same event, say a sport event or a political statement, but since they most likely differ in the presentation, are the content and under laying message of the articles actually the same? A human can read two separate articles and determine if they touch similar subjects and if they approach the subject in a positive or negative way. If this comparison would be preformed over several thousand of articles a computer would very much be the preferred method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic blockmodeling methods for bipartite graphs</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_sbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2021_sbm/</guid>
      <description>Newspapers might report on the same event, say a sport event or a political statement, but since they most likely differ in the presentation, are the content and under laying message of the articles actually the same? A human can read two separate articles and determine if they touch similar subjects and if they approach the subject in a positive or negative way. If this comparison would be preformed over several thousand of articles a computer would very much be the preferred method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A system for GDPR-compliant collection of social media data: from legal to software requirements</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2019_gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2019_gdpr/</guid>
      <description>As of 2018 there is a new regulation regarding data protection in the European union. The legislation, often refereed to as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), has led to increased demands on organizations that processes personal data. This thesis has investigated the legal consequences of social media data collection with a certain focus on collection of tweets. The legal findings was then translated into possible enhancements of a tweet collecting software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text to features for Swedish text</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2019_text_features_swedish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2019_text_features_swedish/</guid>
      <description>In text mining, texts are usually transformed into numerical vectors or feature vectors, before they are given to a machine learning algorithm for text classification. In this project, a set of features for classifying tweets in Swedish was created. The following classification tasks were selected: gender, age and political party prediction, sentiment analysis and authorship attribution, which is the task of determining if a text was written by a particular author or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Detection in Bipartite Temporal Network</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2018_pattern_bbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2018_pattern_bbt/</guid>
      <description>Pattern detection in social networks has been of great interest recently because it helps to reveal insights about how people communicate. In graph mining, this is referred to as a frequent sub-graphs mining problem and it has many variations regarding the structure of the network - i.e. how much information the graph holds. As a part of the evolution of the problem, additional information such as data dimensions or more advanced network structure are incorporated to the input to find more interesting hidden patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Challenge Competition 2019</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2018_cyberchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2018_cyberchallenge/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of a simulated national thread scenario and creation/defense of a policy brief document</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure development and social media analysis using temporal text networks</title>
      <link>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2018_analysis_ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidevega.eu/education/projects/2018_analysis_ttt/</guid>
      <description>The widespread social media usage generates an immense amount of data. Data which is highly beneficial to several domains whether monetary or research based. Various models exist to extract this data however analysis tend to be restrictive. The temporal text network model is a dynamic network model built upon the foundation of temporal networks. It provides text as a variable and considers messages passed between users while maintaining the time of transmission, making it suitable for social media analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
